Curriculum Vitae of Joachim Neumann

If I am not escaping the European winters in Southeast Asia, I live in Barcelona. I am German, 55 years old and have a PhD in Physics. In the last century I used to be a scientist in hearing research, an engineer in a hearing aid company in Copenhagen and since a couple of years I now work as software developer for my own company. Designing medical mobile apps and always be a passion of mine, but I am also happily developing mobile apps, webapps and backends, with iOS apps in swift being my favourite.

I critically look at the ethical aspect job offers and if you think I might be a fit, feel free to contact me over Skype (joachimbarcelona) or by writing to joachim@joachimneumann.com.

Since this is a CV, let me finish with a bit of tabularized information:

Apps

ListenApp by Jacoti bvba (class IIa medical device)
 https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/jacoti-listenapp/id720203800?mt=8
 https://www.jacoti.com/#apps

I was the lead designer and developer at Jacoti for audiological aspects of the hearing aid, including optimizing the user experience for elderly users. I was also responsible for setting up the quality management system and receiving the CE certification for the app and for the management system from bsi (https://www.jacoti.com/regulatory)

• Agedio by IEM (class IIa medical device)

https://itunes.apple.com/de/app/agedio-k520/id968317798?l=en&mt=8 https://agedio.com/de/produkte/b900.html

I have been the lead product developer and programmer for IEM's blood pressure measurement devices and their usage in Pharmacies.

Audimatch by Sonormed (class Im medical device)

https://itunes.apple.com/de/app/audimatch/id1172771164?I=en&mt=8

https://www.sonormed.com/en/#audimatch

I was responsible for the audiological aspects and the calibration of this hearing test, especially for its ease of use by non-trained personnel.

I was also remotely involved in improvements to Tinnitracks

http://www.tinnitracks.com/en

https://itunes.apple.com/de/app/tinnitracks-tinnitus-therapie/id972063556?l=en&mt=8

Safe Listening by the WHO (not released to the market)

https://www.who.int/pbd/deafness/activities/MLS/en/

I was responsible for the audiological aspects and usability of this sound dosimeter, developed together with Hoertech Oldenburg.

See my git repository and iTunes pages for more open source (non-medical) apps: https://itunes.apple.com/vn/developer/joachim-neumann/id741515887

https://github.com/joachimneumann?tab=repositories

I have been involved in other medical apps that are covered by a strict NDA and therefore cannot be mentioned here.

Professional experience

October 2013 – now Independent IT Consultant and founder of Mindo Software SLU January 2012 – September 2013 Head of Development at Jacoti Hearing Technologies, Barcelona

June 2008 – December 2011 Researcher at Telefonica I+D, Barcelona

July 2007 – December 2007 Research in Music Information Retrieval, Universitat Pompeu Fabra January 2004 – June 2007 Research on Human machine interaction in a smart room at the

Technical University of Catalonia, Barcelona, Spain

August 1998 - December 2003 Audiological Research at the Oticon research centre Eriksholm in

Copenhagen, Denmark

January 1997 - July 1998 Hearing aid research at KIND in Hannover, Germany

January 1996 – December 1996 EEG- and MEG-based brain research at the Department for

Clinical Psychology at the Humboldt University, Berlin, Germany

Education

October 1991 – February 1996 PhD in physics with "magna cum laude" at the

Carl von Ossietzky Universität Oldenburg, Germany

August 1983 – October 1991 Master of science in physics (highest grade) on Otoacoustic

Emissions at the University of Göttingen, Germany

Languages

German (mother tongue), English (proficient), Spanish and Danish (fluent)

IT

Profound knowledge in mobile development on iOS and Android, Objective C, Swift, Java, but also C, C++, Python, and DSP programming. Implementation of quality management systems for medical devices.